以下内容根据真实故事改编 部分元素因剧情要求有所删改
声名远扬的斯威尼夫人 我就要娶这位姑娘
The famous Mrs Sweeney. There's the girl I'm going to marry.
一切都和性有关
Everything is about sex.
就像玛格丽特一样
That's Margaret.
开胃菜和鸡巴 你还需要别的吗
Canapes and cock. Is there anything else?
可以的话 甜点吧
Well, hopefully a dessert.
我很喜欢 也非常擅长
I do like it, and I'm extremely good at it.
伊恩·坎贝尔上尉
Captain Ian Campbell.
我喜欢他 喜欢他的城堡
I liked him. I liked his castle.
装满珠宝的沉船
Shipwreck full of jewels.
我从一个非常远房的亲戚那里继承而来
I inherited it all from a distant, distant cousin.
伊恩总是能如愿以偿
Ian always get what he bloody wants.
做我的公爵夫人 你愿意吗
Be my Duchess. Yes?
那么 我愿意
Then yes.
离婚吧 那是我做过最棒的选择
Divorce him. Best thing I ever did.
若不是我如此深爱我的孩子
Perhaps if I didn't love my son so much.
我定不会让你对自己的胜利沾沾自喜 你赢了
I would deprive you of your gloating triumph. You win.
重现因弗雷里城堡的壮丽和雄伟
It's been one of the greatest privileges of my life
是我此生最荣幸的事情之一
to restore Inveraray Castle.
为那些账单付账 就是你的用处
Pay the b-bills. It's what you're for.
每天早上 我都不知道醒来面对的会是哪个伊恩
Every morning I wonder which Ian I'm going to wake up to.
我丈夫阿盖尔公爵不朽的遗产
An enduring legacy for my husband the Duke of Argyll.
那你去世后 我怎么办 这房子是我出钱建造的
What happens to me when you die? The home that I've built.
我儿子会成为公爵 他非常爱他的母亲
My son will be duke, and he's very fond of his mother.
别想把她推到河里或其他鬼主意
Don't push her in the lake or anything.
-我当然不会  -你保证
- Of course I won't. - Promise.
儿子是你的 而不是伊恩的
不许偷看 这可是惊喜
No peeking. It's a surprise.
-我没偷看  -向右转 你在偷看
- I'm not peeking. - Turn right. You are peeking.
我能感觉到你睫毛在动
I can feel the eyelashes moving.
好了 再往前些
All right, a little further.
就快到了
You're getting there.
停... 停下
Stop... stop.
准备好了吗 看
Ready? Look.
一枚炮弹
A cannon ball?
一枚西班牙无敌舰队的炮弹
A Spanish Armada cannon ball.
被埋藏在海床之下整整四个世纪
Four centuries that's been buried under the seabed,
如今成了你的纸镇
and now it's your paper weight.
我们就快找到了
We're getting there.
我的宝藏都安全地存放着
All my treasure will be somewhere safe.
说不定只有两层甲板之遥
Probably two decks down.
我来对地方了
I'm in the right place.
是我让你放手去做的 不是吗
Didn't I tell you do it?
我保证过你会成功的 不是吗
Didn't I promise you you would be the one to do it?
父亲
Father?
老天啊 我给忘了 抱歉
Christ, I'd forgotten, sorry.
是了 得送你们去学校
Yep, got to get you back to school.
玛格丽特 你还记得麦克弗森夫人吧
Margaret, you remember Mrs McPherson?
当然记得
Yes, of course.
我让她来帮你处理些秘书工作
I've asked her to do some secretarial work for you,
她棒极了 无微不至
she's excellent, nothing gets by her.
她丈夫去世了
Her husband died.
我向他承诺会照顾好她
I promised him I'd look after her.
好啊 我一定请她协助
Well, I could certainly use the help.
好极了 走吧我的长子
Marvellous. Come along first-born.
十分抱歉 吓坏你了吧
My apologies. Bit of a surprise for you.
完全不会
No, not at all.
可喜可贺 一大笔家族财富就要物归原主了
Such good news. A great family's fortune is soon to be restored.
对公爵来说真是太好了
Wonderful for the duke.
是对我们俩来说 麦克弗森夫人
Wonderful for us both, Mrs McPherson.
你会来跟我挥手告别吗
Will you come and wave me off?
当然了
Of course I will.
我们回头再讨论我的职责
Then we'll discuss my duties.
还有 请叫我伊芳吧
And please, call me Yvonne.
再见 伊恩
Goodbye, Ian.
-早上好  -早
- Good morning. - Morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
车上的行李都打包好了
The car is being packed.
我们需要在半小时内出发
We'll need to leave in half an hour.
谢谢你 伊芳
Thank you, Yvonne.
请你妥善保管
更多信件将随后寄至
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
我爱你至深 很高兴我的儿子们是你的
而不是伊恩的 你的唯一 路易丝
圣玛丽特酒店
那是什么
What is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
无稽之谈
It's a crank.
这是路易丝的笔迹
It's Louise's handwriting.
别耿耿于怀了
You're not to brood on it.
烧了它吧
It belongs in the fire.
这件事不能传出去
Not a word about this.
你当我是什么人
What on earth do you take me for?
英伦式丑闻
第一季 第２集
你别告诉我你真信了
Are you telling me you actually believe this?
这是你的笔迹
It's your handwriting.
我写过上百封信
I write hundreds of letters.
我从没写过这个
I've never written this.
你在巴黎待得可够久
You spend an awful lot of time in Paris.
人人都在巴黎待了很久
Everyone spends a lot of time in Paris.
我从没住过什么圣玛丽特旅馆
I've never stayed at L'Hotel St Mariette.
听都没听过
I've never even heard of it.
我倒希望我曾不忠过
I wish I had been unfaithful,
那样还能为我们的婚姻增添些愉快回忆
it would've given me some happy memories of our marriage.
他们是我儿子吗
Are the boys my boys?
我以我甘愿为之赴死的儿子们的性命起誓
I swear on the lives of my sons who I would die
你就是他们的父亲 虽然你不配
for that you are their father. You don't deserve them,
但你就是他们的亲生父亲 你这该死的混蛋
but you are their father, you piece of absolute shit.
你一脸愁容
You're brooding.
为什么有人会寄这封信给我
Why would someone send me that letter?
因为人们都莫名其妙的
Because people are very strange.
你该看看我收到的那些玩意儿
You should see some of the things that I get sent.
别再去想了 那些奇怪的恶心小人们
Don't think about it because that's what these peculiar,
正乐见其成呢
nasty little people want.
他们当然是你的儿子
Of course the boys are yours.
毫无疑问
Of course they are.
虽然我和他们的母亲合不来 但我真想象不出
Don't get along with their mother but I can't imagine for a second
她会做出这种事情
that she'd do something like that.
她无趣极了
She's far too boring.
今晚别留我一人
Don't leave me tonight.
陪在我身边
Stay by my side.
当然
Of course.
今晚是你女儿的生日会 会很有趣的
It's your daughter's birthday. It'll be fun.
-爸爸  -珍妮 我的宝贝女儿
- Papa. - Jeanne. Darling girl.
生日快乐 亲爱的珍妮 你看上去美极了
Happy birthday, Jeanne darling. You look wonderful.
玛格丽特 咱们去喝一杯吧
Margaret. Let's go get a drink.
好主意 我快渴死了
Good idea. I'm spitting feathers.
亲爱的 你是找不到伊恩了吧
Dear, have you lost Ian, darling?
他在那边 和他的前妻一号一起
He's over there with, er, wife number one.
当然了
Yes, of course.
谢谢你 亲爱的莫琳 享受派对吧
Thank you Maureen, darling. Enjoy the party.
那是自然
I will.
珍妮 回去找你的朋友们
Jeanne, go back to your friends.
但这边的戏更精彩 妈妈
But mummy, this is much more interesting.
珍妮 出去
Jeanne!
这派对是我出的钱
I paid for this party.
我知道
I know.
至少你可以不要羞辱我
The least you could do is not humiliate me.
不是我在羞辱你 玛格丽特
This isn't about humiliating you, Margaret.
这是伊恩自己的选择
This is about doing what Ian wants
如果不让他如愿以偿 事情就会乱成一锅粥
because not doing what Ian wants is a scene.
你现在一定明白了吧 闹翻天
You must have realised that by now. A scene.
就在这里 公共场合
Right here in public.
我不想这样
I don't want that.
你知道吗
Do you know,
我觉得你无法忍受我做到了你没做到的事
I think you can't bear it that I've succeeded where you've failed?
你觉得我想夺回他吗
You think I want him back?
我们蜜月的第一夜
On the first night of our honeymoon,
伊恩带我去了妓院 他的原话是
Ian took me to a brothel because, according to him,
我要学的东西很多
I had a lot to learn.
我那时才17岁
I was 17.
伊恩夺走了我的一切
Ian took everything I had,
然后他去找薇薇 又夺走了她的一切
and then he moved on to Oui Oui and took everything she had,
等榨干了你的钱 这事不可避免
and when the money runs out, because it will,
他马上想方设法抛弃你
the campaign to remove you will begin in earnest,
如果你不小心的话 你也会一无所有
and if you're not very careful, you, too, will be left with nothing.
你和薇薇可能只是哭哭啼啼的小女孩
You and Oui Oui may be snivelling little girls,
可我不是
but I'm not,
我不需要也不想要你的建议
and I don't need or want your advice.
他就这么走了 你都没阻止他吗
He just left and you didn't try and stop him?
我确实去找你了
I did look for you.
没努力找吧
Well, not very hard.
他开走了我的车 伊芳 我的车和我的司机
He took my car, Yvonne, my car and my driver.
我有车
I have a car.
是辆沃尔沃 没有装饰 还沾满了狗毛
Well, it's a Volvo, no frills, covered in dog hair.
狗毛 让公爵夫人坐吗 我会安排出租车的
Dog hair? For a duchess? I'll arrange a taxi.
不用 我喜欢狗 你是
No, I love dogs. And you are?
彼得·库姆
Peter Combe.
我们走吧
Shall we?
好 走吧
Yes, we shall.
谢谢你 伊芳 晚安 珍妮特
Thank you, Yvonne. Goodnight Janet.
我讨厌这个卫生间
I hate this bathroom.
哪有正常人想在使劲拉屎的时候
Why would anyone sane want to watch themselves as they strain
从各种角度观察自己
for stool from every possible angle?
你可以在别的卫生间里使劲
There are other bathrooms for you to strain in.
我也讨厌那些
I hate those, too.
其实 我讨厌整栋房子
In fact, I hate this whole house.
我喜欢这房子
Well, I love it.
昨晚在那昏过去的时候你可没介意
You didn't mind passing out in there last night.
玛格丽特 你这样就过分了
Margaret. That's a low blow.
你就喜欢在男人处于弱势时攻击他 对吗
You do like to kick a man when he's down, don't you?
如果我喜欢攻击一个处于弱势的男人
If I liked kicking a man when he was down
我就会在那个防滑垫上把你踩碎
I would've stamped you to pieces on that bath-mat.
你开走了我的车 伊恩
You took my car, Ian.
我的车和我的司机
My car and my chauffeur.
看看你 也没事啊
Look at you, you're fine.
你宿醉了 柔弱又美味
You're all hung over and vulnerable and delicious.
不要像对你前妻一样对我
Just don't treat me like your other wives.
天 别告诉我你一直在和珍妮特聊天
God. Don't tell me you've been speaking to Janet.
没有
No.
-你应该放弃  -放弃什么
- You should give it up. - Give what up?
这栋房子 这就是个枯燥无味的冰窟窿
This house. This cold, sterile hole of a house.
别乱说
Don't be ridiculous.
我们会有更多钱
We'd have more money.
你总是在抱怨钱的问题
You're always complaining about money.
放弃吧 这样就不会抱怨了 如何
Give it up, you won't have to complain, will you?
把那艘沉船从海床上捞起来
Get that shipwreck off the sea floor,
我们想有多少房子就有多少房子
and we can have as many houses as we want.
你觉得我做不到 对吗
You don't think I can do it, do you?
你觉得我会把事情搞砸 捞不到沉船
You think I'm going to cock it up. Can't raise a shipwreck.
打仗会被抓 儿子也不是自己亲生的
Can't fight a war without getting captured. Can't father his own sons.
我的老天 伊恩 我说了让你别管那封该死的信了
For God's sake Ian, I told you to ignore that bloody letter,
是谁 是谁总说
and who is it who's always telling
你可以得到你想要的一切 是我
you can achieve whatever you want? Me.
是 你絮絮叨叨地像个保姆
Yes. You do a lot of telling. You're like Nanny.
我才不是你的保姆
The last thing I am is your nanny.
如果我觉得你捞不起那艘船
If I didn't think you could raise that hulk,
我就不会投那么多钱了
I wouldn't have invested so much money in it.
又来了 钱
Here we go again. Money.
我是个讨厌的混蛋
I'm being a horrible bastard.
-对 你是  -你为什么要忍受我
- Yes, you are. - Why do you put up with me?
我不知道
No idea.
我今晚会带你出去吃晚餐
I'm going to take you out to dinner tonight,
以补偿我昨晚屡教不改的
make up for being such an incorrigible,
自私鬼行为
selfish prick last night.
再考虑下房子的事吧
Have a think about the house, though.
-不要  -要
- No. - Yes.
-不要  -考虑下吧
- No. - Just think about it.
上次可没有这样
That's new since I last saw you.
疼吗
Pain?
不疼
No.
只是阵痛
It's just a twinge.
感觉麻木吗 还是像针扎一样
Numbness? Pins and needles?
-都没有  -失眠吗 视线模糊 头疼呢
- No. - Insomnia? Blurred vision? Headaches?
没有 没有 有时候会
No, no, er, sometimes.
还有其他的吗
Anything else?
我想有个孩子
I want to have a baby.
就你的情况来说 有两个孩子已经很幸运了
You were lucky to have two children all things considered,
那还是在你失足跌下来之前
and that was before your fall.
但那已经是几年前的事了
But my accident was years ago.
就算你成功怀胎十月 这可能性还不大
If you manage to carry the child to term, and that is a big if,
我不确定你是否能够挺过生产过程
I am not certain you'd survive the labour.
现在医学都这么发达了
There's been so many advances in medicine.
这可能会让你丧命
It could kill you.
别 不用管
No, leave it.
戴安娜 亲爱的
Diana, darling.
你竟然自己开门
You're answering your own door.
乌鸦离塔了吗
Have the ravens left the tower?
[如果乌鸦飞离伦敦塔 那就意味着伦敦塔及大英帝国将遭遇厄运]
公爵去哪了
Where's Il Duce?
他一整天都在上议院 关于...
He's at the House of Lords all day, something about...
我不知道 也不在乎
I don't know and I don't care.
走开吧
Go away.
你发誓此事绝不外传 戴安娜
Now I'm swearing you to absolute secrecy, Diana.
好吧 我保证 什么事这么着急
All right, fine, yes. What's the urgency?
说啊
Well?
我要你帮我买个男婴
I need you to buy me a baby boy.
什么
What?
一个新生男婴
A newborn baby boy.
我会付钱 高价
I'll pay. I'll pay very well.
你嫁给了波兰人 你肯定人脉很广
You're married to a Pole. You must have lots of contacts,
肯定也有穷苦姑娘
and there must be some poor girl somewhere who wants
想给她的孩子最好的一切
to give her baby the best of everything,
你知道的 美妙的人生
you know, a wonderful life.
不过那孩子得长得像伊恩
The baby does need to grow up tall like Ian, though,
所以你最好认识孩子的父母
so it's probably best that you know the parents.
上帝
Jesus.
你是认真的
You're serious.
玛格丽特 不是你疯了 就是我疯了
Margaret, either you're having a nervous breakdown, or I am.
戴安娜
Diana.
不 太糟了
No, it's too awful.
不 应该是太震惊了
No, it's too shocking.
伊恩的儿子不是他的
Ian's sons aren't his.
他们是私生子
They're illegitimate.
继承人和备选 两个都是
Both of them. Heir and spare.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
伊恩收到了一封信 匿名的
Ian got a letter, anonymous.
上面说他们有证据
They say they've got proof.
这是典型的敲诈勒索而已
Well, that's just standard extortion.
不是的 寄信人没要钱
No, they don't want money.
他们只是想拨乱反正
They want to right a great wrong, set matters straight.
他们是其他男人的儿子
They're some other man's sons,
一直被该死的薇薇冒充成伊恩的儿子
passed off as Ian's by bloody Oui Oui this entire time.
薇薇吗
Oui Oui?
她看上去不是这种人
She doesn't seem the type.
她就是 她报复心可重了
She's the type. She's completely vindictive.
所以 伊恩需要一个子嗣 因为他不可能
So, Ian needs an heir because he can't possibly leave anything
让他们继承任何东西吧
to them now, can he?
你真的了解英国贵族们吗
Have you met the British aristocracy?
私生伯爵和杂种男爵们满地都是
It's rammed with bastard Earls and by-blow Barons.
每个人都视而不见
Everyone turns a blind eye.
我计划周全了 先垫个大肚子
I've thought it all through. I start to pad my waist,
让人们悄悄议论起来
let people whisper about it.
开始散播谣言
Start the rumours,
然后我会去一家瑞士的诊所
and then I go to a clinic in Switzerland,
之后你就给我带个漂亮的男宝宝来
and then you bring me a beautiful baby boy,
而我会给你很多钱
and I give you a lot of money.
-我以为你是我朋友  -我是 并且作为你朋友
- I thought you were my friend. - I am, and as your friend
我要跟你说 别掺合
I'm telling you, just don't get involved.
伊恩的儿子和你没半点关系
Ian's sons are nothing to do with you.
如果不是我和我爸 因弗雷里早就荡然无存了
Well, Inveraray wouldn't exist if it wasn't for me and Daddy.
它就是颓垣断壁 男孩们什么都继承不了
It would be a ruin and those boys would have nothing to inherit,
所以是的 这一切都和我有关系
so yes, it has everything to do with me.
玛格丽特 在你引火上身之前 去度个假吧
Margaret, go on holiday before you get yourself in trouble.
戴安娜 我要你发誓保密
Diana, I swore you to secrecy
如果你告诉任何人 我会知道你就是个大嘴巴
so if you tell anyone I'll know that you can't keep a promise.
去度个长假吧 阳光好的地方
A long holiday. Somewhere sunny.
宝贝
Hello, darling.
你说过要带我出门吃晚餐的
You said you'd take me out for dinner.
你知道吗 议会开太久了
Do you know, the House sat late?
是的
Yes, it did.
但你不在那儿
But you weren't there.
对不起 我在俱乐部
I'm sorry. I was at the club.
不
No.
你也不在那儿
You weren't there, either.
你的间谍军团们真厉害
Your legion of spies, duh, duh, duh, duh.
又醉了 你昨晚就醉了 现在也是
Drunk. You were drunk last night and you're drunk now.
长脸婆今晚嘴有点碎呢
Fish-face is being a little nag tonight.
浑身是别的女人的香水味
You reek of other women.
-是吗  -你先和别的女人厮混 然后就这样回来见我
- Do I? - You've been with some other woman, then you come back to me in this state?
我的天 资产阶级就是会逼逼个不停
My God, this relentless bourgeois whine.
真他妈烦
It's so fucking boring!
夫人
Your grace.
亲爱的
Oh Dear.
看看你让我做了什么
Now look what you've made me do.
我把佣人们都吵醒了呢
I've gone and woken the servants.
你为何要这样
Why are you being like this?
我一整天的好心情都被你毁了
I had such a lovely day and then you've gone and spoilt it.
我去俱乐部睡吧
I'm going to sleep at the club,
明早我们坐第一班火车回因弗雷里
and tomorrow morning we go back to Inveraray first train.
我不回
I won't be.
我让你做什么事 你就给我立马去做
You'll do what I tell you to do, and when I tell you to do it.
你是不是把我跟你前妻搞混了
You must be confusing me with one of your other wives.
真高兴你有空
I'm so glad you were free.
亲爱的 为了你 我永远有空
Darling, for you, I'm always free.
所以今晚干啥 喝酒还是跳舞
So, what's the menu tonight? Drinking or dancing?
-都要  -答对了
- Both. - Right answer.
两杯马提尼 谢谢
Two martinis please.
我那么爱你母亲
I loved your mother so much.
你还有我呢 爸爸
You've got me, Daddy.
我永远在这儿
You've always got me.
你不该没和我讨论就把伊芳开了
You shouldn't have let Yvonne go without discussing it with me first.
我们雇不起她 伊恩 我们得省钱
We can't afford her, Ian. We have to save money.
而且 我没什么活要她做
Besides, I didn't have enough work for her.
-她不能就这么无所事事吧  -有何不可 你不就是吗
- She can't just stand around doing nothing. - Well, why not? You do.
我给她找了另一份工作
Look, I got her another job,
还准备跟她吃顿午饭作为补偿
and I'm giving her lunch to make up for it.
和你共进午餐 真是中大奖了
Lunch with you. What a treat.
妆真吓人
That's terrifying.
你以为我想做这个吗
You think I want to do this?
你以为我想自降身份给阿盖尔袜业打广告吗
Do you think I want to debase myself advertising Argyll socks?
接下来你会要我去卖
You'll have me selling
印着家族徽章的外科束带
surgical trusses with the family crest on it next.
给得多的话 有何不可
If it pays well, why not?
或者你可以放弃这间房子
Or you could give up this house?
或者你可以放弃你的寻宝游戏
Or you could give up your treasure hunt?
准备好了 阁下
We're ready, Your Grace.
好了吗
You done?
挺身临其境的
It's just like being there.
你想让我站哪
So, where do you want me?
我今晚出去吃晚餐
I'm out for dinner tonight.
笑一下
Smile.
超棒
Super.
很遗憾你母亲去世了
I was very sorry to hear about your mother.
谢谢
Thank you.
新工作还不错吧
And are you enjoying your new job?
他们是很慷慨的雇主
They're a very generous employer.
太好了 让你走我也很舍不得
I'm very glad. It was difficult to let you go,
希望你能理解
I hope you understand that.
伊芳 能问你个问题吗
Yvonne, can I ask you?
你认识伊恩比我久 他和你丈夫
You've known Ian longer than I have, and he and your husband
还是那么好的朋友
were such good friends,
他一直都这么不可理喻吗
has he always been so impossible?
一直酗酒
The drinking.
阴晴不定 我完全摸不准他的心情
He can be so changeable, I can barely keep track of his moods.
公爵当下有很多心事
Well, the Duke has a lot on his mind at the moment,
不过我不懂为何你觉得他不可理喻
although I don't see how you can tell that he's impossible.
你都没在他身边
You're never with him.
你... 什么意思
I... beg your pardon?
你一直说你有多爱因弗雷里
You keep talking about how much you love Inveraray.
我确实爱 那是我家
I do. It's my home.
可你一直在这里 和男人们厮混
But you're always here, going about with men,
他们年龄还是你的一半 如果你多陪陪伊恩
men half your age. If you spent more time with Ian,
像个称职的妻子一样扶持他 那也许他
supporting him as a proper wife should then maybe he wouldn't
就不那么不可理喻了
be so impossible.
我懂了 所以错在我
I see. So, it's my fault.
-我认为你还不够努力  -不 我很努力
- I don't think you try hard enough. - No, I try.
真的吗
Do you?
那你还让他拍那种广告 你怎么忍心
And as for that advertisement, how could you?
如此贬损和羞辱一个男人
Debasing and humiliating a man like that,
让自己的丈夫为量产的袜子吆喝
your own husband forced to shill for mass produced socks.
伊芳 我邀请你是把你当朋友
Yvonne, I've invited you here as a friend,
你却跟我说这种话
and you choose to speak to me like this.
你邀请我吃午餐 是想让我赞同你的观点
You invited me to lunch because you want me to agree with you.
或许是会因为 你以为我会留下只言片语
Perhaps because you thought I'd drop some hints,
关于可怜玛格丽特的流言蜚语
some gossip about poor Margaret,
以及她对公爵百般忍让
and how she suffers with the Duke,
这女人是多么高尚 你根本不是什么圣人
what a saint that woman is. Well, you're no saint.
我为伊恩感到难过 他值得更好的
I feel sorry for Ian. He deserves better.
伊恩一直觉得你工作做得很糟糕
Ian always thought you were terrible at your job.
如果不是我 你甚至待不到两个月
If it wasn't for me, you wouldn't have lasted two months.
如果你要说谎 麻烦让它变得可信点
If you're going to tell lies, do try and make them plausible.
你知道吗 伊芳 我觉得你忘了一个
Do you know, Yvonne, I think you've just remembered
非常重要的约会
a very important engagement.
我觉得你是对的 确实忘了
Do you know, I think you're right. I have.
帮伊恩打包好去英格兰所需的所有东西
Make sure Ian packs everything he needs for Scotland.
他需要的是一位妻子
He needs a wife.
就这样吧 我们停工吧
That's it. We're shutting it down.
探索结束了 阁下
The exploration is over, Your Grace.
拜托 求你了 我们快成功了
Come on, please. I beg you, we're nearly there.
别现在停下啊 我都说服皇家海军了
Don't stop now. I'm working out with the admiralty,
你们可以待在船上 可以... 回去
you can stay in the boat. You can... you can get back to it.
就差临门一脚了
We're so close.
结束了 阁下
It's over, Your Grace.
约翰·佩特罗医生来拜访公爵 他在等我
Dr John Petro for the Duke. He is expecting me.
我失败了
I've failed.
伊恩
Ian?
-怎么了  -我失败了
- What is it? - I've failed.
不不 你没有 我们尽力了
No. No, of course you haven't. We tried everything.
我们都尽力了 只不过这是痴心妄想
We both did. It's just it's not possible.
我想把它留给我的孩子们
I wanted it for my boys.
他们是我的儿子
They're my boys.
是我的孩子
They're mine.
他们当然是
Of course they are.
阁下 佩特罗医生来了
Your Grace? Dr Petro.
亲爱的 老家伙
Dear me, old boy.
你状态糟透了
You are a mess.
他体温飙升 还在胡言乱语
He's got a raging temperature and he's not making any sense.
不好意思 夫人 但麻烦您出去
I beg your pardon, Your Grace, but I need privacy.
我就在外面 亲爱的
I'll be just outside, darling.
我看到你给公爵开了安非他命
I saw that you prescribed amphetamines for the Duke.
对 促进他的系统循环
Yes, to boost his system.
我还以为是铁剂
I would've thought that an iron tablet,
鱼肝油对治疗更有帮助
cod liver oil would've been better treatment.
而不是安非他命
Not amphetamines.
他的行为... 反复无常
His behaviour... can be very volatile.
你之前给我丈夫也开这种"补剂"吗
Have you given my husband this boost before?
我是来这治疗你丈夫的肺炎的
I'm here to treat your husband's pneumonia.
你算哪门子医生
What sort of doctor are you?
公爵的医生
The Duke's.
这次你要去见哪位情人呢
Which one of your lovers are you seeing this time?
彼得·库姆吗
Is it Peter Combe?
老天 彼得只是送我回来
God's sake. Peter escorts me.
太多女人围着他转 我找他还得预约
He's got so many girlfriends, I'd have to book him in advance.
我要去银行开会
I've got a meeting with the bank,
如果能对我们的经济状况有帮助 我愿意上了经理
and if I thought it would help OUR situation, I'd ride the manager,
员工都会喜欢切尔滕纳姆赛马冠军的
and all the clerks like the Cheltenham winners.
不 你就希望如此
No, you like it like this.
你很高兴沉船还陷在海底
You're glad that shipwreck's buried under the mud.
是吗
Am I really?
这样你就能控制我 趾高气昂
It means you can still control me, prancing around
自称公爵夫人 把我的炮弹装进你的手提包
calling yourself a Duchess with my balls in your fucking handbag.
反正也不占什么空间
Well, it's not as if they take up much room.
亲爱的
Dear.
现在都不配放进去了
Now you've lost your place.
你嗑得太多了 这对你身体不好
You take too many of those. They're not doing you any good.
它们能阻止我往自己脸上来一枪
They stop me from shooting myself in the face.
你有过多少个男人
How many men have you got?
至少八十个 可能不止 你呢
At least 80. Probably more. How about you?
你有过多少个女人
How many women have you got?
当然 我可以往你脸上来一枪
Of course, I could just shoot YOU in the face.
你可以...
You could...
然后你会因为谋杀被绞死 这样我就赢了
but then you'd be hanged for murder and I'd win,
想想你有多不喜欢这结果
and think how much you'd hate that.
你看 我们就是如此般配
You see, this is why we're a match.
薇薇和珍妮特会潸然泪下
Oui Oui and Janet would've burst into tears,
但你不会
but not you.
你是个街头小霸王
You're a little streetfighter.
刚涂完口红
Lipstick.
既然你提到了她
Now that you've mentioned her,
对于薇薇和那封信
have you decided what you're going to do
你有决定要怎么做吗
about Oui Oui and the letter?
听取专业意见之后 我决定什么都不做
After taking professional advice, I've decided to do nothing.
专业意见
Professional advice?
我去了苏格兰场 跟警长谈了谈
I went to Scotland Yard, spoke to a Detective.
他说这种事时常会发生
He said this sort of thing happens all the time.
再加上他们在圣玛丽特酒店什么都没发现
Plus they found nothing at L'Hotel St Mariette.
他们说什么都别做
They said do nothing.
那些人最终会自食恶果的
They'll trip themselves up in the end.
我很高兴你跟别人谈过了
Well, I'm glad that you've spoken to someone,
然而你却对我只字未提
though you never mentioned it to me.
为什么要呢 他们不是你的孩子
Well, why, would I? They're not your children.
你要跟你爸聊聊钱的事吗
Are you going to talk to your father about money?
伊恩 他还处在丧妻之痛中 我不想问他要钱
Ian, I don't want to ask him for money while he's still grieving.
我真的爱你 你知道吗
I do love you, you know?
尽管如此
In spite of it all.
我是真的爱你
I do love you.
别担心你的炮弹 我会好好保管的
And don't worry about your balls. I'll keep them safe.
别跟我说你不知道 亲爱的
Don't tell me you didn't know, dear.
百万富翁乔治·惠格姆
在卡克斯顿厅堂结婚
不 我当然知道
No, of course I did.
他们只是想 保密
They just wanted to keep it, er, secret,
私下进行 毕竟妈妈才过世没多久
you know, private, being so soon after Mummy,
但毕竟摄像师无孔不入 所以
and there's photographers everywhere I go, so.
你不想抢了新娘的风头
You didn't want to steal the bride's light.
你真是太无私了
You are so selfless.
堪比天使
Utterly angelic.
这对夫妇立即动身前往巴巴多斯度蜜月 真好
The couple departed immediately for a honeymoon in Barbados. Adorable.
你的继母比你还年轻
Your new stepmother's younger than you.
你爸真是个狡猾的老家伙
Your daddy is a sly old dog.
你确定你没事吗
You're sure you're OK?
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
我觉得跟你打电话很蠢 我也不知道我怎么想的
I feel silly telephoning you. I don't know what I was thinking.
不 没事的
No, it's OK.
我只是担心你 就是这样
I was just worried about you, that's all.
老天 他来了
God, here he is.
我看着太丑了
I look a fright.
玛格丽特
Margaret?
不如改天再告诉他吧
Why don't you just tell him another night?
让咱俩安安静静去吃顿饭
We could just have a quiet little dinner, just you and me.
不行 亲爱的
No, darling.
不行
No.
抱歉破坏了你今晚的计划
Sorry for ruining your evening.
没... 没有
No... No you didn't.
没计划 一直都是
No plans, as per.
有事打电话
Er, call me.
不
No.
拜托了
Please.
态度... 好... 好点
B... B... Be nice.
我知道应该怎 怎么做
I know how to b-behave.
诚挚的祝福和敬意 乔治
Salutations and congratulations, George.
谢谢 你好 你好
Thank you. Hello, hello, hello.
-简  -见到你很开心 你好
- Jane.  - Lovely to see you. Hello.
-终于得幸见您一面  -谢谢
- Enchanted to meet you at last. - Thank you.
宝贝女儿
My darling daughter.
-快进来坐  -谢谢
- Come in and sit down. - Thank you.
这一趟怎么样
So, how was the journey up?
-挺久的 对  -挺久的
- Very long. Yes. - Long.
来到这真好
It's nice to be here.
我们先吃顿午饭缓一缓
Well, let's have a spot of restorative lunch,
然后我带简参观花园
and then I'll take Jane for a tour of the garden.
天啊 这里...
Gosh, it's, erm...
好美
It's beautiful.
我本来应该告诉你的
Of course I should've told you
但是我为她神魂颠倒 自从你妈妈去世后
but I was swept off my feet. I've been so lonely,
我一直很孤单
you know, since mother.
我会一直陪着你的
I would've kept you company.
伊恩在午餐就喝醉了
Ian was drunk at lunch.
我们都喝了香槟
We were all having champagne.
我们到的时候 他已经醉了
He was drunk when we arrived,
我见识过他在俱乐部喝酒
and I see the way he drinks in the club.
大家都喝酒 爸爸
Everybody drinks, Daddy.
他是借酒消愁 这你知道
He drinks for oblivion, and you know it.
爸
Daddy?
别让我再接济伊恩了
Please don't ask me to bail Ian out again.
我不会赔了夫人又折兵
I'll not throw good money after bad.
知道了
I see.
你知道那是多少钱吗
You understand about the money?
当然
Of course.
你觉得简怎么样
And about Jane?
你过得开心就好了
I just want you to be happy.
开心 很开心
I am. So very happy.
你跟你爸说过钱的事儿了吗
Did you talk to him?
说过了
Yes.
然后呢
And?
不给
No.
不会再给钱了
There's no more money.
你还要对我不理不睬多久
How long am I going to get the silent treatment for?
可悲
Pathetic.
看着你在简面前魅力四射
It's especially sickening
对我却闷声不吭 真是恶心
to watch you be completely charming to Jane and then foul to me.
对简好很简单
Well it's easy to be lovely to Jane.
她很甜美 很性感
She's delicious and sexy.
你家老头要想上她 得先吃点欧芫菁[能壮阳]
Your old man's going to need Spanish Fly to keep up with her.
跟了这么个老头 真是浪费
She's wasted on him.
你想干什么
What are you for?
你到底想说什么
What is the point of you?
你想干什么
What are you for?
我要进来了
I'm coming in.
我现在就进来
I'm-I'm coming in right now.
阁下
Your Grace.
需要请医生吗
Do you need a doctor?
彼特罗医生
Dr Petro.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我觉得警察应该很感兴趣
Well, I'm sure the police would be very interested in a doctor whose
一个医生的咨询室竟然是这么个脏地方
consulting rooms is this sordid hole,
病人还在外面排了老长的队
and whose patients queue up outside.
找我什么事
What can I do for you?
别再给我老公开安非他命了
You are going to stop giving my husband amphetamines.
中断和他的所有联系
You'll cease all contact with him.
他的身体健康也与你无关
His health is no longer your concern.
明白了吗
Do we understand one another?
很好
Good.
夫人 关于公爵在克拉里奇酒店开了间套房 您怎么想
Your Grace, any comment on the Duke taking a suite at Claridge's?
抱歉 不过你错了 我丈夫现在在苏格兰
I'm sorry, but you're wrong. My husband's in Scotland.
如果他在伦敦 肯定会跟我在一起
If he was in London, he'd be with me.
不 公爵在克拉里奇酒店
No, he's he in Claridge's.
听说你们的婚姻已经结束 有什么要说的吗
We've been told your marriage is over. Any comment?
拜托 你肯定知道点什么 公爵夫人
Come on, you must know something, Duchess?
公爵夫人 公爵夫人 简要说下吧
Duchess? Duchess, a quick word?
-您好 这边请  -公爵夫人
- Hello, here we go.  - Duchess?
果然是你 他人呢
Of course it would be you. Where is he?
他不想见你 公爵夫人
He doesn't want to see you, Your Grace.
你跟他说什么了
What have you told him?
我什么都没说 我没有跟任何人说
I haven't told him anything. I haven't told ANYONE anything.
我想见我丈夫
I want to see my husband.
算了 别把事情闹大 他不想见你
Please, don't make a scene. He doesn't want to see you.
她说的话我一个字都不信 她就是个骗子
I wouldn't believe a word she's saying. She's a liar.
-所以我不想让她为我工作了  -公爵夫人
- That's why I don't want her working for me any more.  - Duchess?
-她真是个麻烦精  -公爵夫人
- She's a deeply troubled woman.  - Duchess?
你试着帮助别人一把
You try and help people,
但是他们不仅不领情 还倒打一耙
and they just throw it back in your face.
他为什么要离开你 公爵夫人
Why's he leaving you, Your Grace?
他去哪了
Where is he?
你好
Hello?
求你了 回来吧
Come back, please.
伊恩
Ian?
求你过来
Please come.
我... 我受不了了 过来吧
I... I can't bear it, please come.
你在哪
Where are you?
巴黎
伊恩
Ian.
-晚上好  -谢谢
- Bonne nuit.  - Merci.
我不知道为什么要去克拉里奇酒店
I don't know why I went to Claridge's.
我不知道为什么那样说 那么做 我真的不知道
I don't know why I say and I do the things I do. I don't.
有时候 你让我很害怕 伊恩 你伤害了我
You frighten me sometimes, Ian, and you hurt me.
你不给我钱
You wouldn't give me money.
我一直觉得你在骗我
I kept thinking that you were lying,
你背着我做了很多事 然后还骗我
and you were going behind my back and you were lying.
我觉得这段关系还可以修复
I think we can make it work between us,
真的
I really do.
但我们要善待彼此
But we have to be kinder,
不要再互相伤害了
stop doing terrible things to each other.
你做什么伤害我的事儿了
What terrible things have you done?
没有 只是... 在伦敦待得太久
Nothing, just... ..being in London too much.
虽然跟在公共场合羞辱我比不算什么 但还是伤人
It's not quite the same as humiliating me in public, but still.
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
你应该对不起
Yes, you should be.
对不起
I'm sorry.
药和酒 都不能再碰了 伊恩
The pills and the drinking have got to stop, Ian.
好
Yes.
-永远别碰了  -好
- For good.  - Yes.
我们会没事的
We'll be all right.
午餐 圣玛丽特酒店
滚开
Piss off.
圣玛丽特酒店